{
    "id": "ad77f719a9cb45989429da201f8d36c3",
    "title": "English Vocabulary Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The fox tried desperately to free itself from the trap. Which of the following words means ‘free’?",
            "description": "Extricate means free, untangle or liberate.",
            "answers": [
                "exuberant",
                "extenuate",
                "extricate"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "da2b491f7e5c4165b1b6916cd998de18"
        },
        {
            "question": "The students rejoiced at the last day of school. Which of the following words means rejoiced?",
            "description": "Exulted means rejoiced.",
            "answers": [
                "exalted",
                "exulted",
                "extolled"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "52e6e9e78fe14235a076d4dd04371004"
        },
        {
            "question": "The king was honored by his subjects. Which of the following words means honored?",
            "description": "Exalted means honored. Exulted means rejoiced.",
            "answers": [
                "extolled",
                "exulted",
                "exalted"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "91ebc1a6221441e5bee85f55a63f7af3"
        },
        {
            "question": "When the guest speaker failed to arrive, the chairman of the club gave an unprepared talk on environmental issues. Which of the following words means unprepared?",
            "description": "All of the above words mean unprepared.",
            "answers": [
                "extemporaneous",
                "impromptu",
                "extemporary",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "83c467e4e80d44488099444156954696"
        },
        {
            "question": "He was not fined for speeding because his need to get to the hospital quickly was a justifiable circumstance. Which of the following words means justifiable?",
            "description": "Extenuating means justifiable or explanatory.",
            "answers": [
                "extemporaneous",
                "extenuating",
                "extraneous"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "66427c82fcd343b2a13e4085df08b7ee"
        },
        {
            "question": "The witness’s irrelevant remarks were struck from the record. Which of the following words means irrelevant?",
            "description": "Extraneous means irrelevant.",
            "answers": [
                "exquisite",
                "extraneous",
                "expedient"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e55151eab59a49bfa24b296b3a360b32"
        },
        {
            "question": "Using postal codes quickens the delivery of mail. Which of the following words means quickens?",
            "description": "Expedites means quickens ",
            "answers": [
                "expedites",
                "expends",
                "exonerates"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b737bbd5ba134e51878eaf5fa8dbde29"
        },
        {
            "question": "During World War II many German refugees settled in the United States. Which of the following words means refugees?",
            "description": "Expatriates means refugees.",
            "answers": [
                "compatriots",
                "expatriots",
                "expatriates"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "e7b0ff19f3764399b256bce5cd22a45b"
        },
        {
            "question": "The older boy’s admirable behaviour had a good influence on the younger. Which of the following words means admirable?",
            "description": "Exemplary means admirable, emulative, commendable and similar ideas.",
            "answers": [
                "exemplary",
                "exhilarating",
                "exacting"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "dcb6c944483f4d1a92a2af108eea062a"
        },
        {
            "question": "The deceased was lauded by his closest friend. Which of the following words means lauded?",
            "description": "Eulogized means highly praised or lauded.",
            "answers": [
                "eulogized",
                "lampooned",
                "languished"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "7bb8853d4fed46c3962e155dda070962"
        },
        {
            "question": "Shun fattening foods if you want to lose weight. Which of the following words can mean shun?",
            "description": "Eschew means abstain from, steer clear of",
            "answers": [
                "eschew",
                "abdicate",
                "abstain"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "83fc85487e1742b08da7a606cc4a4180"
        },
        {
            "question": "Some fields of science seem hopelessly cryptic to the layman. Which of the following words means cryptic?",
            "description": "Esoteric can mean incomprehensible.",
            "answers": [
                "esoteric",
                "aesthetic",
                "exasperate"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "3e48b041bf2f486292d1922be09f7533"
        }
    ]
}